[Music]
good evening and good day everyone
welcome to episode 23 of the ask a
budget show
today we discuss indian history which i
think is everyone's
favorite topic so let's get right into
it
i have a very interesting bunch of
questions let's start with
question number one
so this is by nishant i want to know
whether the ramayana or the mahabharata
were contemporary to the indus valley
civilization
so to answer this question we need to
essentially know the date
of the ramayana and the mahabharata we
as of today
don't know when these two episodes very
important and pivotal episodes of indian
history happened we don't know when they
happened
there are a number of claims by various
researchers and scholars and
historians etc but none of these claims
has been proven
so we don't know when these things
happened uh we can
possibly guess a little bit as to when
maybe the mahabharata could have
happened etc
maybe when the ramen could have happened
but we don't really know when it
happened and
therefore we can't really answer this
question we know that the ramayana seems
to have happened during a much earlier
phase of indian history compared to the
mahabharata which came later
but it could
either of these could have coincided
with the
indus valley phase maybe they could
maybe maybe they did not
uh we can approximately guess about the
ramayana when it could have happened by
dating the ram setu
if the government would go ahead and
take the initiative of dating
this man-made structure the ram sithu
then we could get an idea of when the ma
when the ramayana happened
and if we could accurately date the
sunken city of dwarka as to when it sank
into the ocean
then we could get a rough idea of when
the mahabharata happened
and then based on these dates we could
see whether it coincides with the indus
valley or harappan
phase or saraswati river phase of our
civilization or not
so as of today we can't really answer we
know that
the ram saturday is at least 7000 years
old but we don't know exactly when it
was constructed
we know that there has been some carbon
dating done in the ancient
sunken city of the dwarka they found a
piece of wood which was dated to
dated uh to around 8 000 years before
today or thereabouts you know
roughly so these give us some rough
indication but
we don't really have conclusive proof of
when these events happened
and there are certain like i said lots
of claims based on archaeoastronomy but
those are very conflicting claims
and none of those claims has been
established beyond doubt so as of today
we can't say
and therefore as of today we don't know
we know the date the approximate
chronology and timeline of the
harappan phase of our civilization but
we can't tally it with the mahabharata
or
so as of today this is one of the
unanswered questions
of indian history and this is something
we need to work
on understanding more about
prathamesh asks can you uh
shed some light on rakigari what is the
importance of the site other than the
various
indus valley civilization sites that we
know already
so rakiguri is in northern india north
western india
present-day haryana it's it's not very
far from delhi i believe
maybe 100 200 kilometers from delhi
so that's what it is and it is its
significance is that it is the
largest known archaeological site of the
harappan phase of our civilization
so i don't know its exact area maybe 500
600 or more
hectares or so if i am not mistaken
something like that
it's the largest that we know of and
it's also one of the oldest
sites uh so it's it's uh
it's been uh excavated partially it's
been known for some time
there has only been some partial
excavation they found some human
skeletons there
they found a symmetry they also found
skeletons from which dna was recovered
and some and and the the genetic
analysis of one of those specimens was
done
so that sheds a little bit tiny bit of
light on the
uh ancient indian genetics of that time
and there there are a lot of artifacts
that you find over there which
and lots of lots of valuable artifacts
etc
have been found there and unfortunately
many of them have been plundered
and that's been going on for years and
years and unfortunately our treasures
are being
basically sold out you know they're
being they're being
plundered and sold to various places let
me show you an example of what's
happening so this is a let me share this
this is a news report from uh i think
it's from 2015 yes 2015.
it says the rakhikari site is being
plundered due to lack of protection
lack of official protection and plunder
of treasure troves hidden underneath by
unscrupulous element
elements are playing havoc with the five
thousand plus year old ancient site
so there is lack of official protection
there is plunder of treasure troves
uh encroachments illegal
sand lifting etc antiquities being
recovered from the site had been sold
over the past many years many people own
antiquities etc
and they're selling it off uh
etc i mean that's what's happening over
there
uh the asi has deployed a watchman at
the site who has been transferred two to
three times since he was careless
and so on so the asi has deployed
his has deployed one watchman at this
incredibly
significant historical site so basically
the treasure from from the site are
being plundered and sold off
let me show you some examples of that uh
this
is if it will load this is an
international online art auction
antiquities auction website in which you
can see india's valley and
ancient uh such artifacts being sold
check out the prices two thousand four
fifty dollars two thousand four fifty
dollars etc
eighteen fifty dollars these are all our
ancient
artifacts these this is our ancient
heritage that is being sold off online
so it's already in the hands of these uh
collectors
who are now selling it off online check
it out all of this is our ancient
heritage it's been sold off by
this is obviously a european or american
person somebody from the west who is
selling it so they have acquired it
somehow
from either from india or from pakistan
or from both
so this is our ancient heritage that's
being sold off you can see
what this is right let me show you
another example of this
here is another example let's wait it
wait for wait for it to load this is
called vatican.com
and this again here is our ancient
heritage from the sindhu region
i'm not saying it's all from rakhigarhi
i'm not saying it's all from india it's
from pakistan as well
but some of it is definitely from india
this is called vatican.com if you can
see my mouse pointer
so our heritage is being sold off in
this manner online
and like the like i showed just now this
this blunder has been happening in
rocketry as well for many years
so this is the kind of job the
archaeological survey of india is doing
in protecting our heritage so the
rakigiri site is the
largest most extensive and one of the
oldest and it has
incredible amounts of these ancient
artifacts this
which are very valuable on the online
circuit among antiquities collectors
and these are being sold off in in
troubles
to to various such people
in the west who auction them off online
so that's what's happening and that is
what our wonderful asi is doing
very unfortunate okay next question
this is by chetan why didn't the british
loot the treasure of the ananta
padmaswamy
banantapad banaba swami temple in kerala
which is worth
which is trillions of dollars in in
value
what prevented them from doing so i
believe
they never came to know about this and
neither neither did the turks who had
who
occupied large parts of india at some at
a point in time
so i think the uh the temple authorities
the royal family etc
whoever was in charge of the temple they
successfully
uh managed to prevent
the foreigners the foreign occupiers of
india from coming to know about the kind
of treasures
that are there in the temple these walls
have been locked off for centuries i
mean you have found
lacks of ancient roman gold coins and
and treasure from
treasures from mesopotamia and and
greece and various various other parts
of the world
so it seems that these uh valuables had
been donated
to this temple for thousands of years by
people from rome by people from greece
by people from mesopotamia as well it
seems
and by indians who traded with these
places and by indians within india as
well because india was the richest
civilization of all time
in antiquity so this has been
happening because in the sangam uh
literature this temple
is mentioned it's mentioned as a golden
temple as a temple whose
whose walls are made of gold so that is
about two and a half thousand years ago
so it was already an extraordinarily
wealthy temple
two and a half thousand years before
today right so it's
the wealth that this temple has managed
to preserve is
thousands of years old and they somehow
managed to
uh prevent the foreigners from from
coming to know about this right
and today the indian judiciary has
forced the temple to divulge all of its
treasures
and the i think the local kerala high
court tried to
put this wealth in the hands of the
state government the communist
government which was
frightening to say the least and it
seems that
the supreme court has again reinstated
control over the temple
to the travancore royal family who i
think will definitely do a better job
so so i think that's the reason why they
somehow managed to save the treasures
and they prevented
anyone from knowing about it and
especially the foreigners right
so the value of the wealth is estimated
to be at least one trillion dollars in
of worth in today's dollars and there is
one vault that is still
unopened so that may be even more
valuable who knows
and so the question is what is to be
done with this wealth i think it belongs
to the temple it is the donations of
the faithful over thousands of years to
this temple so i think the temple
authorities should decide what is to be
done with it
i do not want to be it to be used by any
form of government whether the
state government or the central
government who will misuse it as has
been done for the past 70 years
temple wealth has been stolen for
decades in this country
and it's been used for secular purposes
which we know what what they are
so i hope that this treasure is is
preserved
and it is uh it is not uh spoiled
right
this is from meenakshi the gupta dynasty
the gupta dynasty came after the
mauryans then why do we know
more about the mauryans than we know
about the guptas that's a good question
meenakshi
so it's because our historians our our
post-independence historians and even
though the pre-independent
even the pre-independent british
historians of india emphasized
more about the mauryan dynasty because
the
the nice thing for them about the modern
dynasty is that it had this great king
ashok
so-called great king who converted
as if there is a conversion from
buddhism into
from hinduism into buddhism so he
converted supposedly
after in engaging in this disastrous
kalinga war which caused so much death
and destruction and
and and anguish and misery so he
as a hindu went into this war and then
after the seeing the misery he converted
to buddhism that's the official line
and that's what makes it so attractive
to india's post-independence neherubian
secular communist marxist historians
right
who have always tried to portray
hinduism as evil
and anything that is not hinduism as
good
so that's why the mauryans are so
attractive to them and that's why they
have tried to portray ashok
they've tried to distort the story of a
show can portray him as some great
benevolent noble king who converted
after the war
actually he there is no first of all
there's no conversion from hinduism to
buddhism or vice versa
right it's the same thing and secondly
he he began
practicing the precepts of buddhism much
before
the the kalinga war actually happened so
that's one thing but they have been
lying about it
right and the guptas were out and out i
mean they basically practiced
what is mainstream hinduism not the both
the dharma form of hinduism
so the the guptas they themselves were a
shining brilliant dynasty they had
samudra gupta one of the greatest
emperors of all time in india right he
was another
emperor who who unified the whole of
india under one
central uh dominion he ruled from partly
putra
so these so if you if you study the
history of the gupta
empire of the gupta dynasty then it
makes hinduism look good right
so that's why their uh contributions and
their
role in india's history their their very
significant
role in india's history has always been
downplayed you hardly get to read
anything about the gupta
empire in india's history textbooks and
it's always more as more is more is
glorification of the mauryas
so it's because of this political agenda
that india's marxist
historians these neherubian historians
have been
have been trying to further and that's
still happening right
so that is the reason why we are taught
about the mauryans but not about the
guptas the guptas were a
wonderful dynasty very powerful very
significant dynasty
i think samudra gupta samudra gupta was
basically known for
conquering most of india and he was a
very good emperor
he was a vigorous campaigner he was an
expansionist he defeated all the kings
in india more or less right
and he did not kill them all he
basically allowed them to continue on as
his vassals
and he is known to have conquered
india the indian peninsula southern
india indian peninsula
and both the oceans the western ocean
and the indian
in the eastern ocean knew of some other
gupta's glory
that is what is recorded about him and
his
empire stretched from all the way to the
east
to or to all the way in the west
afghanistan so he was another
very significant emperor as great as any
mauryan or or
maybe even more right so that's the
reason why
these uh agenda-driven marxist narrative
historians do not want
the people of the people of india to
know about the
gupta dynasty
okay akash asks after all the modern
historians in the asi for that matter
are tilted towards obscuring and
distorting india's real history
why this is being done by this being
done by europeans is
understandable but how come they do it
indian historians do it and the asi does
it
against their own country good question
so it basically ties in with the
question i answered just a minute ago
we know why the west does it western
historians are driven by their
euro-centric
occidentalist uh agenda
that orientalist agenda to to portray
the east as inferior
and less able than the than the
europeans
right so we understand we understand why
they do it now why do
india's historians do this well there
are a couple of reasons for this
first of all nehru our our great
magnificent prime minister shri
jawaharlal nehru
he wrote this history of india it was
called the discovery of india or
something like that i have never read
the book unfortunately
i have read many books but i have not
read that book so in which
in this book mr shree describes the
history of india from the very beginning
to the very end apparently
but on various occasions he expressed
his disdain
for hinduism and for hindu temples and
all that so it was very clear what sort
of
cultural affinities he had right
his affinities were basically anti-hindu
and that becomes basically anti-indian
so the agenda of the historians under
his regime
was to distort the history of india and
make hinduism look bad and weak
and powerless and evil and oppressive
and backward and primitive and then
castes and misogynistic
and you know you know the rest right so
that's what they have
they tried to do by manipulating the
history in the textbooks and
portraying india's history in a certain
fashion that's number one
now after sri nehru passed away to our
eternal regret uh the the
regimes that followed his regime
continued the very same thing
and later on unfortunately the marxists
or the communists were put in charge of
india's academic
india's history textbooks and the entire
academic system
and the agenda of these people is very
much the same it's even
more vitriolic it's even more vicious
they essentially want to eradicate
all traces of indian culture they will
start with hinduism when hinduism is
gone they'll go on to buddhism
eventually they want to introduce
foreign
cultures into india that that is the
ultimate objective because marxists are
for sale
okay every marxist has a price they act
as
agents of various powers internal
external you can think
i mean we know all we all know what that
is so their agenda is to divide and
destroy
and therefore they have gone even
further in doing this
today every academic department in this
country whether it's the humanities
whether it's the iit's
two is infested with these marxists
the even the iits in india are full of
these humanities departments right
and these are basically marxist snake
pits
so their agenda is very simple to divide
the country on on the basis of all kinds
of
distorted versions of history and
distorted sociology etc
and that's why they have engaged in
doing this so they have basically
uh after the 70s or something like that
they have
written all of india's history textbooks
if you see the authors of the ncrt et
cetera textbooks most of them are
marxists
and that's why they have been distorting
history and also
you cannot be a historian in india
unless you you
you get on with this with this program
right you will never be allowed to be an
academic
of any repute or any you will not be
able to
be get any promotions etc in the
academic system unless you
go along with this agenda and again
these people are given stipends and and
various inducements from abroad
we know that very well the every single
indology department in the west is
essentially anti-hindu and they give
various
inducements etc to these indian
academics
so if you get with the program then you
will get
to go on foreign trips and go to travel
business class
and stay in three-star or four-star
hotels
in the west etc and you will be made to
look like you are a successful
academic and a and an eminent historian
so these are the reasons why these
people have been doing this for decades
it's still happening
nothing has been done to stop this rot
the worst thing is that even the iits
indian institutes of
technology are spending a significant
amount
of their budget on these humanities
departments and if you look at the
professors in these humanities
humanities departments and the kind of
research these people are indulging
in it's all along the same anti-india
and the hindu lines
so that's what's happening in this
country and we are funding that with our
taxpayer money
isn't that nice
aditya asks why are indian
philosophies neglected from the
mainstream philosophy
and in india despite the fact that it
had every topic like epistemology
ontology psychology metaphysics physics
etc this is an excellent question sir
so you are absolutely right indian
philosophy has been totally neglected in
india's
philosophy curriculum you go to any
philosophy department in india
and you see the curriculum they'll teach
you about plato but aristotle about kant
hegel
they will teach you gandhian philosophy
whatever the hell that is
they'll teach you about krishnamurti
they will teach dalit philosophy
whatever that is
they'll teach you about the frankfurt
school about critical theory
about feminist philosophy etc
but they won't teach you anything
significant about indian philosophy
and indian philosophy is way older and
way richer
than all of this right and these schools
of western philosophical thought have
been borrowing from indian philosophy
for
centuries without ever acknowledging the
fact that they are
borrowing from us right so there are
indian philosophy is vast it is it is
enormous
there are so many schools of thought at
least seven uh
major significant schools of thought and
we just don't know about them we think
everything comes from the west
let me tell you a little bit about in
philosophy so you have
seven eight nine schools of indian
philosophical thought major
and there are way more uh subsidiaries
subsidiary schools and other schools
so the nine major ones are charvaka jain
uh both
sankhya yoga mamsa and vedanta these are
these are nine major schools
so charvaka is materialism it says that
perception is the only valid source of
knowledge
the material world is the only reality
the existence of god is a myth
the vedas are false and wrong and the
highest aim of life
is the enjoyment of the greatest amount
of pleasure so this is pure materialism
this is charvaka it is one of the major
schools of thought of indian philosophy
it is part of hinduism so this is an
atheistic school of thought it is part
of hinduism then you have
jaina the jaina philosophy which rejects
the charvaka view that perception is the
only source of knowledge
jaina says that inference and testimony
are also valid sources
the jaina school of thought comes from
24 thirteen comes tirthankars
of whom the twenty third was parsonath
in the twenty fourth the last one
was mahavira so the jaina school of
thought believes in the
beliefs in the existence of souls it
says souls exist
humans animals plants microorganisms
even dust grains have souls but not
every soul is equally conscious
some are more conscious about less
conscious and according to the jaina
school of thought the aim of existence
is of liberation liberation by removing
all the accumulated
karmas of of the different
incarnations by following the teachings
of the tirthankars
the liberated saints and the jaina
school also is an atheistic
school of thought because it rejects the
existence of god
then you have both the philosophy about
the philosophy is about the four noble
truths
number one there is misery in life
number two
there is a cause of misery number three
there is a cessation
of misery and number four there is a
path that leads to the cessation
of misery and this is the so-called the
the eight-fold
noble path of buddhism in buddhism the
aim of existence is the cessation of
misery the cessation of the cycle of
rebirths
it is to attain enlightenment or nirvana
then you have nyaya which is a school of
thought that
owes its existence to the great sage
gotham
this is a realistic philosophy based on
logic
there are four separate sources of true
knowledge pratyaksha anuman upaman and
it says that the self the atma is
distinct from the mind and from the body
and again the ultimate aim is the
liberation of the soul
and nyaya believes in the existence of
god then you have vaishyasik which
owes its origin to the great sage and
scientist
canada so according to washington there
are
there are seven categories of substances
nine kinds of substances
four kinds of atoms which are invisible
in destructible particles of matter
and therefore the vaishyasik school of
philosophy
is the first quantum theory
according to this theory the mind is
eternal it's infinitely small
like an atom so there is a quantum of
mind as well
and the ultimate aim again is the
liberation of the soul
and according to this theory god exists
then you have sankhya which is dualistic
realism which owes its existence to the
sage kapil
you have yoga which owes its existence
to patanjali
right you have me mansa which owes its
existence to germany it is based on the
vedas
which is again an atheistic school of
thought
right it says that whatever the vedas
command
want to perform is dharma and what they
forbid is wrong
it says the soul is immortal and eternal
but there is no supreme soul
or creator god it says that the law of
karma is the
autonomous natural and moral law that
rules the world
and finally you have vedanta which
arises from the upanishads
it's considered to be the culmination of
vedic thought
according to vedanta there is a supreme
person who permeates the entire universe
and yet remains beyond the universe
so as you can see these are different
models
of the universe these are different
theories these are
so uh so detailed
and and these these are vast schools of
thought
you can spend an entire lifetime just
researching one
and that is the entirety of indian
philosophy and there is much more beyond
it
so it is it is incredible that indian
universities colleges etc do not teach
about this in
any detail there is some cursory
reference to these things but
unfortunately
none of this is taught in any detail and
in indian philosophy
uh like i said these are different
models of the universe these are
different
theories proper theories philosophical
theories unfortunately indian philosophy
stopped evolving 1000 years ago
with the destruction of our great
indigenous universities
and today in india's modern colonized
universities
they teach western philosophy so that's
a great
tragedy i wish this were to change
sometime soon
anthrax asks what are your views on baal
gangadhar tilak's arctic home theory
and the connection of orion to the vedas
so this uh
arctic home theory i think it was
published in
the early very early 20th century maybe
1901 1904 or something
like that so this theory was
uh by like you said it was based on the
evidence
and the information and the knowledge
that was available in the 19th century
and based on this information he came up
with this
idea this theory this hypothesis that
indians originated in the arctic circle
now with the evidence that we have today
it is
it is clear that this is entirely
incorrect
right so this is an outdated theory
it's an obsolete theory and it's an
incorrect theory
it doesn't mean that mr balangadathira
was a
was a bad scholar it just means that the
information he had at his disposal
was incorrect it was 19th century
information today we have much more
information
we have much better information we have
scientific information from a variety of
fields
from from genetics from archaeology from
from
geology and in many other many other
fields right
so we know better today so that theory
is irrelevant today we don't even need
even need to discuss it
it is part of the history of history
right
so that's an incorrect theory it has no
relevance today
krishna asks please tell about india's
historical ties
with balochistan what relations did we
have
did india ever face an invasion from
balochistan
so talking about india's historical ties
with balochistan is like talking about
india's historical ties with gujarat
or india's historical ties with with
orissa
or india's historical ties with kashmir
you can't have historical ties with
yourself balochistan has been for ten
thousand years plus
it's been a part of india right it is
part of the
uh the sindhu region the westernmost
extreme of the subtess in the region
and there are there there have been
found
uh these harappan era settlements in
balochistan
as well so it is historically a part of
india so
what do i talk about our ties with
ourselves right
so it is the basically the westernmost
extremity of jambudweep the ancient
indian
continent or the indian subcontinent and
the people
who live there today are very much
indian by ethnicity
they're indian by culture their religion
is different that's the only thing
if you look at their their language and
their their
traditions and culture it is closest
to the people of sin than gujarat and
rajasthan
so they are essentially the same people
as the people of sindh gujarat rajasthan
so that's what it is it's the same
country it's the same land it's the same
people it's the same ethnicity
it's the same culture it's an accident
of history that balochistan
is temporarily not part of india it will
soon again be part of india
reasonably soon i am confident of that
okay while new studies proving that
ravan sri lanka existed
proving that ramanasalanka existed
somewhere near the maldives
and not present-day sri lanka how do we
find
ram sethu and how to contradict the
existence of present-day sethu
which is made of limestone not present
anywhere in the vicinity of hundreds of
kilometers there
hmm interesting question you have asked
sir
so i am not aware of any study that
proves the existence of lanka
anywhere except in sri lanka
what is proof so you're saying it's
somewhere near the maldives
so have we found any island near the
maldives
that's question number one question
number two is have we identified that
island
unequivocally as the ancient blanker
so the answer to question number one is
no we have not found any island near the
maldives
two if we have not found any island near
the maldives how do we
how can we even identify that as the
lanka of
the ramayana i am aware of certain
individuals who have claimed who have
made the claim
that sri lanka is not the historical of
the ramayana
maybe it exists somewhere else has have
any of these claims been proven
no absolutely not
i think it is preposterous to to say
that it has been
proven i'm not trying to make this a
reflection on you but i am saying that
it is completely impor it is completely
incorrect
to say that such a claim has been proven
a claim is proven when there is
independent corroboration and
verification
of that claim so what needs to be done
to prove such a claim is that
an independent team of scholars
scientists researchers
need to examine the evidence or the
logic
behind this claim and agree with it
independent teams of researchers has
anyone done this
i i don't think anybody has i am aware
of the fact
that nobody has so this claim
is completely unproven and as far as i
can see it is unfounded
okay so from my perspective there is
only one lanka
which is the present-day sri lanka and i
and there is clearly a rama setu there
so we need to be careful about what we
construe as proof
and we need to be careful careful about
not taking a claim
made by one individual as the gospel
truth
any claim has to be proven has to be
confirmed independently by independent
teams of researchers in a scientific
manner it has to be proven with science
okay and therefore this uh
and therefore i cannot agree with i
cannot agree with this uh
this theory that some other lanka exits
someone and it has been proven
it has not been proven such claims if
they exist
they have not been corroborated by
anybody at all so this is where we are
with regards to this
question as far as like the best
from the best evidence that we have
today from the best information
from the best knowledge the best data
that we have there is only one lanka
which is
sri lanka
this is by vishal gandhiji propounded
the principle of
non-violence throughout his life but he
considered it
a duty of indians to fight for the brits
for the british in world war one
and other wars this conflicts the very
idea
of non-violence my views on this
you're right this does come into
conflict with the very idea of
non-violence i mean
mr gandhi expected indians to
not resist the british through violence
but he expected the people of india to
to take up arms
weapons and go to distant shores
on behalf of the british occupiers of
india
and fight for them and die for them
so this is mr gandhi's non-violence
right i mean is there any logic in this
is there any
moral consistency what what is the
principle behind this is there any
principle behind this is there any ethic
is there any ethical principle behind
this i don't see any
and there are many many other
contradictions to mr gandhi
right he spoke he propounded
non-violence he insisted on non-violence
and yet he forced the congress party
to accept srineru as the first prime
minister of india
even though they had voted for mr sardar
patel
so even though there was a democratic
election within the indian national
congress
and the unanimously or near unanimously
voted for
sardar wala by patel as the first prime
minister of india
mr gandhi threatened them
threatened to go on a fast until death
and therefore forced
them by this means to reverse their
decision and
accept mr nehru as the prime minister
even though mr nehru did not get any
votes
so isn't this an even worse form of
violence this is moral violence isn't it
so these are my views on mr gandhi it is
time to re-examine mr gandhi's life and
career there are many questions about mr
gandhi's life
let me ask a few questions what was mr
gandhi doing in south africa during the
two decades plus that he was there
when you are in a foreign country you
need a source of income
was he practicing as a lawyer did he how
many court cases
did mr gandhi fight in south africa and
what was his income from these court
cases
or was somebody else funding his stay in
south africa
how did he acquire a big farm a big
commune in which he
had many people who lived there and who
paid for this farm
who paid for these people's sustenance
who paid for everything there
what is the source of all this income
why did mr gandhi never reveal or
disclose or divulge these
sources of income and when mr gandhi
came back to india on whose behalf did
come back to india
and who parachuted him to the leadership
of the indian national congress almost
overnight how did that happen so there
are many questions
unanswered questions about mr gandhi we
need to
critically re-examine mr gandhi's career
in its entirety
we need to go through every word that he
wrote and he wrote
hundreds of thousands of words in
writing
these are all available online we need
people to go through this to sift
through these words
and to uncover the real mr gandhi it is
high time we do this
okay our freedom struggle is most of the
time
non-violent but in the west all other
countries used
violent ways to get freedom
why did we not use any violent ways to
get freedom
and we might also have got freedom early
through violence you
are right sir so mr gandhi came back to
india in the
second decade of the 20th century i
don't remember the exact year
maybe 1915 to 1920 thereabouts i think
probably
closer to 1915. so at that time
within a very short period of time mr
gandhi became the undisputed leader of
the congress party and he was
viewed as a saint almost overnight in
india now what if he had commanded the
people
people of india go out on the streets
and kill the british
kill every single british person you see
it doesn't matter if you die
you're gonna die anyway your only job
of you 300 million indians go out on the
street
you kill one british person then go home
so if 300 million people
in 300 million indians went out on the
streets with the objective of just
killing one british person each
then every single foreign occupier of
india would have been dead within 24
hours
i know some indians would have died
maybe a few thousands maybe a hundred
thousand
maybe a million indians would have died
and yet every single
occupier would have died and it would
have saved
millions of indian lives because they
killed so many millions of indians
after 1920 in a variety of ways
including
artificial famines so
my point is mr gandhi by not resorting
to violence by not allowing the people
of india to resort to violence
delayed india's independence by at least
two decades
right so that's the thing and my
question is
whom does non-violence serve
what is the purpose of violence i mean
when you have
a conflict in your family let's say with
an
aunt or an uncle or siblings you
obviously don't resort to violence that
is not the right way to do it
and even within the country when you
have a conflict within your country you
don't resort to violence these are your
own people
so it is morally and ethically wrong to
resort to violence when it comes to your
own family
or your own country people because these
are your own people they are your own
blood
you need to resolve it amicably through
non-violent means
but when it comes to the foreign
occupiers
who have intruded into your country
conquered your country
occupied your country illegally and are
plundering its wealth
and killing millions of your country
people it is completely justified to go
and kill them all
and therefore my question is whom did
gandhi's non-violence
serve that is the question i would ask
you my friends
go ahead and comment about this whom do
you think gandhi's non-violence
served did it serve the people of india
did it serve certain sections of india's
population did it serve mr gandhi
himself
or did it serve the foreign occupier
akash asks if anyone asks me
who or what was responsible for freeing
india what shall be my answer because as
far as i know the whole credit is given
to gandhi
while i think instead of this his credit
is due on breaking india so if not him
then who
let's understand what happened
during british during the british
occupation of india
they wiped out every royal family they
installed puppets
in their place i'm not saying every
single member of every single
royal family died many of them still
survive today they are
living in poverty etc the real royalty
of india was
was marginalized if not wiped out right
that is number one the british stole
the almost the entirety of india's
wealth india's gdp was 33 percent of
that of the entire world
by the time the british british left
india had two percent of the world's gdp
right india's life expectancy was less
than 30
years by the time the british left and
before the british came to india even
during the
turkic occupation most indians had land
they had their ancestral lands
that had been passed on from generation
to generation for thousands of years
the british deprived every indian of
their land they instituted the riot
worry system
in which every in in which the land was
confiscated from all indians
and every indian farmer in every indian
industry was destroyed
and every indian the vast majority of
indians more than 200 million indians
were forced to indulge in subsistence
farming
either either growing uh food crops or
cash crops
and so basically they stole the land of
every indian
and they gave these lands to various
zamindars and various british
stooges after independence
these lands were not restored to any of
the indians who lost their lands to the
british
and these zamindars and these people who
benefited from british largest
they are the big industrialists the
hereditary industrialists who still
are wealthy today many of these
old industrial families in india owe
everything to the british
and the people of india who lost
everything to the british they were not
given any justice after independence
they were not given the lands back in my
opinion
upon the stroke of midnight on 15th of
august
every indian should have been given a
parcel of land of this country
that's what makes them citizens
everybody had land before
the british occupation today how many
people actually own land
very few very few people in india
actually own land if you see if you
if somebody were to compile the
statistics the statistics would be
shocking
so most indian citizens don't own land
in india
and a small number of people own great
amounts of land
the largest non-government
land owner in india is guess who
it's the catholic church so
why were these injustices not redressed
upon independence
these indus injustices have been allowed
to persist
the people who benefited from british
occupation of india they are still
benefiting from it
so did we really get independence that's
my question
we are still following british laws the
laws that the british wrote
we still have a foreign constitution
which is not indian in nature or origin
the institutions that govern us and rule
upon us
are the institutions the british made
and there has been no justice land
reforms nothing
nobody has been given the land they lost
or their ancestors lost
so where is this independence that we
talk about the independence that we are
supposedly enjoying is an illusion we
have never become independent
we are continuing the same system we're
still speaking the same language
if i were to speak in hindi half my
audience would disappear because half of
india doesn't understand in the
south of the southern parts of india
because hindi is almost like a foreign
language for them because it is so urdu
eyes
and personalized and arabized and that's
why we have to rely upon a foreign
language
to unify this country as of now so
where's the independence
there's no independence we are still
trying to decolonize
independence happens occurs only when
you decolonize and you undo
the policies that the british
had implemented in india so that's never
happened
so i don't really believe that we have
ever got independence from british rule
we are still continuing the same system
right
so yes gandhi gets the credit for
breaking india
so so does jinnah to a small part so
does the congress party to a great
extent
they also get a great deal of credit
credit for
uh slowing down the progress of india
after 47
but in my opinion india has never really
become independent we are still
colonized in a variety of ways
especially mentally
we still see ourselves as inferior to
this british or to the westerners
or or to people who have a lighter skin
tone than ours
so we need to change our mentality and
we need to
find a way to reform the system
and it we are tired of
gradual incremental reforms we need
revolutionary reforms
to unleash the real india so that's what
we await we await real independence
rakesh asks the history of slavery in
india
the history of slavery is in india is
very short it begins with the turkic
invasions of india the turkic occupation
of india and later the british
occupation of india
it ends with the withdrawal of the
british more or less from india
indian culture has never practiced
slavery ever
even the greek sources from 2000 years
ago say that the indians don't practice
slavery
there's not a single slave in india
every other foreign source corroborates
this fact that indians did not ever
practice
slavery in india's history textbooks
today you will
you will be taught that india had
slavery because the marxist
historians or distorians interpret the
sanskrit word
dasa to be meaning slave
dasa means servant not slave but they
have translated it
as slave right so that is the reason why
indians believe there was slavery in
ancient india
when somebody when a king had a number
of dasa it means they had
servants servants are paid people right
you have public servants today other
slaves hell no
so so that's the thing so indians never
practice slavery
slavery is abhorrent in indian culture
in any of the schools of thought of
of whether you call it hinduism buddhism
jainism sikhism whatever
slavery is unacceptable in any form of
indian culture
it is the turks who brought it into
india and later the british who
who institutionalized it in a variety of
ways by calling it indentured servitude
or whatever
so it is the foreigners who brought
slavery into india
and it is with their departure that
slavery ended
siddhant asks how come bihar from being
one of the most
prosperous and advanced regions
of ancient bharat became one of the
poorest states
of the country you are right bihar
is the seat of a number of ancient
empires
magadha was bihar basically
partly putra was the capital of magadha
paklipur was the capital of the mauryan
empire
partly buddha was the capital of the
shonga empire
it was the capital of the guptas it is
one of the most significant
cities in the entire history of india it
was the capital of india for ages
and the region which is now called bihar
was one of the most prosperous
regions of india as was bengal as was
everything else
right so how did did it go how did it
decline
from where it was to where it is it all
happened with the turkic invasions
bihar was the seat of learning was one
of the major scenes of learning
the great university of nalanda was in
bihar
so it is with the destruction of nalanda
by the turks by the burning of this
great library and the destruction of
various other
universities and viharas and the
destruction of temples
and the various massacres that happened
that the decline of bihar happened as
as did the decline of the entirety of
india and it is after independence that
the
so-called cow belt region of india which
is european bihar
was increasingly marginalized by the
nehemian regime
because that is the heartland of india
the ganga valley etc
and bihar also is essentially uh
an extension of that so it is this uh
disdain for the uh for the ancient
heartland of indian culture that led the
nihin regime to marginalize the
this region and that's why bihar has
been for generations
been neglected and that's why it is in
the state it is today
one hopes it soon regains
its its its former glory it's one of the
greatest regions of india
it's one of the greatest cultural seats
of india the people
because of poverty they may not think
very much of themselves today but they
had brilliant and great ancestors so i
hope to see bihar
rise again and rise again soon
akash asks sher shah suri is portrayed
as a great king in our textbooks
that he fought against the invader
barber and
made the grand trunk road etc how much
of it was for india and how much was it
for himself
so this uh individual sher shah suri
well one thing that goes for him is that
he was not a turk he was an indian
he was from the suri clan which is a
north indian clan
it's you find the suri surname in punjab
as well as in afghanistan
excuse me
so depending on how you look at shersha
he was either afghan pastor
or punjabi or even bihari or whatever
but he was indian he was native
so that's one thing that that goes for
him now this guy sher shasuri was in
power in
in north india in northern india for
five years
five years and it is his
arch enemy humayun who praised him to
the high heavens
that he was the uh he was a teacher of
kings and all that that sort of thing
so this guy shirsha he did some reforms
which are glorified to the high heavens
in indian textbooks
uh he repaired an ancient road the
so-called grand trunk road
he did not make that road fyi that is a
very ancient road
it was it it was in existence during
chandragupta maurya's time
it was called the ut in in india
in ancient indian history so this road
stretched
from the uh borderlands of
india to the east to the from the
myanmar border in the east
all the way into afghanistan and into
central asia so that was the uttara path
that was a major road in india during
the
time of chandragupta maurya chandragupta
maurya had maintained this road
very well there were innumerable rest
houses and inns
and even dispensaries for human beings
as well as for animals
along this road everything was free fyi
for all the travelers
so it's a very ancient road shirsha may
have merely repaired some portions of
this road
and there is a very dark side to share
shasori as well in his
merely five years of rule he perpetrated
a number of atrocities
many massacres in the region of malwa
east of gujarat
he treacherously
committed a massacre of rajputs there
was this rajput king who
small chieftain who had submitted to
sheriff's suzerainty
and despite submitting to this these
guys in suzerainty shersha
massacred this small chieftain along
with ten thousand men women and children
uh it was a horrific incident and many
of the women and children were taken as
slaves
and you can guess what happened to them
so that is the kind of individual
suri was he was as brutal and as
inhumane as any of the turks so i do not
see
any greatness in this individual
whatever reforms he may have done
may be good in the eyes of the marxist
historians not in the eyes of any
civilized or decent human being
sher shah suri was a monster that's what
he was
gargi asks pranam gargi is it true that
before the abrahamic invasions and
terror established by the same in bharat
the viva sanskar was performed in broad
daylight
unlike today during or after midnight
especially in the states of
bihar up jharkhand especially basically
north india northern india
also if possible can you give an idea
about the last bihar magadha
faced in terms of wealth and power and
intellectually and culturally
due to invasions was there any massive
resistance on the part
from bharat so let me answer the first
question the first half
is it true that before the invasions
especially the turkic
invasions were weddings conducted in
broad daylight
in northern india it's a very good
question
so you know in the british isles
uh in in old days maybe 800 900
000 years ago there was this custom so
first of all scotland and ireland had at
various points in history
being conquered and occupied by england
scotland and ireland are separate
distinct
culturally etc from england england was
the big bully the big oppressor
so at various points in time england
occupied scotland
and ireland and they would uh install
lords to govern various regions of
scotland and ireland
these lords were basically brutes they
were they were brutal people
really evil people so there was this
custom
there was a despicable custom in this in
that these english lords practiced
so whenever a scottish lady would get
married
the local english lord would
take her with him on the day of her
marriage
and return her to her husband the next
day
he would bless the marriage by doing so
and this was called
prima nocta in in latin first night
in french it was called the uh
the right of the lord so this is a
despicable custom the british practiced
and the turks in india practiced
something just as despicable
but in india they would
indulge in this bride hunting on the on
the day of our marriage and they would
not just
abduct the bride they will also kill the
bridegroom and various members of the
wedding party etc
and you can guess what happens to the to
the bride so this
is the reason why weddings in northern
india
had to be conducted in the dead of night
in
complete secrecy and very quickly so
after midnight and thereabouts
and over the years decades and centuries
this became
the regular custom the regular practice
it became tradition
and that's why it still persists today
they have forgotten the reason why this
was instituted in the first place
today there is no need to conduct
weddings in the dead of night
so this is how it happened it has a very
very
sordid uh origin very very unfortunate
so that's the reason why weddings are
conducted in the date of
night in northern india to answer your
other questions
yes like i said bihar did face a great
deal of loss in the terms of wealth
in terms of education and culture all
the universities were destroyed the
vihars the mahaviraharas
the universities temples etc
so yeah that's what happened in bihar
and as with every other part of india
the people of bihar did resist
heroically
but here we are today so that's your
answer
gargey
anusha asks some say that subhash
chandra bose had dictatorship ideas for
india
is it true i do believe that he did
state this on at least one occasion that
india needed
at least 20 years of iron fisted rule
of of one-man dictatorship in order to
bring india out of the clutches of
colonialism and and poverty and all that
so he did
express that opinion now is it right is
it wrong well
who's to judge that see singapore
if we take the example of singapore
singapore was under a dictator
lee kuan yew and he brought singapore
out of poverty
it transformed it from a third world
country to a first world country
in just one generation in 20 years so he
did exactly
what washington said but he did it in
singapore
not in india and if you look at
places like china and vietnam
they went their own way they went the
communist dictatorship way
right and they refused to follow any of
the
guidance the guidance given by western
economists
out of spite and out of disdain and out
of hatred for them
and see the direction that china went in
and see the direction that vietnam went
in
they have both progressed immensely
economically
so we have to understand that sometimes
dictatorship
does work especially when you have a
country that is in the dumps that has
been destroyed by colonialism
and a country that is deep into poverty
sometimes
a strong man rule does work wonders
so you have a number of examples you
have singapore you have china you have
vietnam
that have risen out of poverty very
quickly after
a dictatorial rule and even south korea
is another example you had a one-party
rule there too
a one-man rule for for many years so it
is entirely possible that subhash
chandra bose
had he come to power had he succeeded
and had he
instituted a dictatorship on over india
for 20 years it would have brought
india out of poverty much faster so
subhashindrabosu's very was very clear
about what kind of government he wanted
in india
he wanted a liberal government a
one-party rule a one-man rule
he wanted complete equality everybody
should have the same rights
he wanted complete freedom of religion
and culture so everybody can
practice any religion or culture they
want and he wanted massive
industrialization massive economic
development
so he in a way
espoused similar ideas as narrow massive
industrialization
etc but nehru botched it up very badly
nehru was incompetent bose
could have been much better so i agree
that sebastian rabos did intend to
become
a dictator in india and i don't think i
don't know if it was a bad thing
it i'm sure anything would have been
better than what nehru did in india
it's all hypothetical but yeah so this
is this is true yes
okay about um
johan defeated muhammad gory in the
first battle of taran
but he was defeated he was eventually
defeated in the second battle can you
please explain
the reasons behind this well
okay just a minute
so the first battle of taran happened i
think in
1191. forgive me if the date is wrong
but i think it's 1191.
so this is a battle in which this this
fellow muhammad gauri
invaded india from the northwest he was
based in ghazni at the time
in gandhara which is now afghanistan
and the major king in india was
prithviraj johan
and these two met outside
of tarawi present-day tarawi in aryana
and pratyura chauhan smashed
the afghan army and
for reasons known only to him
he allowed muhammad gauri to return to
afghanistan
and the very next year in less than a
year
or maximum one year the battle happened
again this guy went back to afghanistan
he was wounded
he went back to afghanistan he recovered
he built another army
and this time he knew how the rajputs
fought so they met again
in the same location on the same
battlefield and this time
the army of india was defeated and thus
began
the infamous uh
gory rule over india the korean dynasty
which eventually
spread all the way or stretched all the
way to bangladesh present day bangladesh
so why did the indian army lose
so it's because prithviraj johan for
whatever reason decided
to forgive muhammad gauri and allow him
to he allowed him to go back
this was the stupidest decision any
indian ruler has taken in
and one of the most significant
decisions
one of the most infamous decisions any
indian ruler has taken
in the past 1000 years and please do not
construe this as
anti-rajput sentiment or anti chauhan
sentiment i cannot be anti raj
rajput or anti chauhan i am speaking as
an indian
prathura chohan made a disastrous
blunder
it was a very stupid decision when you
have an enemy who is intent
on destroying you destroying your
country enslaving your people
and you have defeated him and he is at
your mercy
how on earth can you let this individual
go back scot-free
as the leader as the ruler of law of a
large part of india
johannes duty was to serve his
nation and his people and put their
interests above any ideology or
or or chivalry that he may have had
his personal belief about forgiving the
enemy
is not important the long-term future
and prosperity of his people and of his
country
was more important and he betrayed his
people and he betrayed his country
right and do you even know what happened
to his wife sanyogita
after he died do you even know what
happened to the womenfolk of his of his
land
after he died so prathurad johan
betrayed his people
by allowing muhammad gory to go back
after
he defeated mohammed gauri and that that
basically was the turning of the tide
when it comes to the
to the uh turkic etc
invasions of india so that is the reason
why johan lost the second battle
because he displayed all his tactics and
strategies to gauri
in the first battle then allowed him to
go back
so gory came back with with all the
knowledge of how to defeat
praturaj this time
harsh asks you had called all the
surviving royal families british puppets
were maharana pratap singh's descendants
puppets as well
okay maybe i did not express myself
clearly enough
okay if there is a case i apologize so
here is what i meant
what i said or what i meant to say is
this
in 1857 we had the first
war of independence in the against the
british occupation of india
so all the uh this was basically almost
a nationwide war
many of the royal families in india
fought against the british
eventually as we know the british
prevailed
and all of these royal families who
fought against them
were wiped out they were either all
killed
or those who managed to escape were
basically marginalized forever their
descendants may still survive today
but they lost everything they had
and then the british installed puppet
kings
in their place these are the so-called
princely states that we know of and and
some of these royal families
may not have fought the british there
are certain uh places like
baroda for example or or mysore
i'm just giving some random examples i'm
not sure it's entirely accurate
but there are some royal families that
did not fight the british and cooperated
with the british
either willingly or against their will
so those were allowed to continue and
the ones who fought were either wiped
out
or they basically vanished into
obscurity
so what i mean to say is that those who
cooperated with the british
are the puppets those who were installed
by the british after 1857
are the puppets those who are today's
princely states or or who are the
descendants of those princely state
families
today are the descendants of puppets the
original royal families
were not puppets they are the ones who
fought
and died for india and their dece some
of their descendants do
do survive today they are the
descendants of india's heroes
so not everyone was a puppet sir
maharana pratap was not a puppet
his descendants are not puppets the ones
who cooperated with the british
they are the puppets and the ones who
were installed by the british
are the puppets the others are not
puppets
they are the descendants of heroes i
hope
that clarifies this matter
okay one more question
raj asks india now wants a permanent
seat in the u.n
why did former pm nehru reject it
so the great prime minister shri nehru
yes you are right
he rejected an offer
that was made to india it was not just
one offer there were two offers made to
india the first
offer was made by the united states and
the ussr
together in 1950
they offered a permanent seat on the u.n
security council
to india and our
great statesmen like prime minister shri
jawala nehruji in a fit of magnanimity
said that
india does not want this please give it
to china instead we will not do this at
the expense of china china needs to be
put first
so the matter went to went to rest for
some time
then once again in 1955
the united states and the ussr again
together
came together and offered once again
us a permanent seat on the u.n security
council to india
and once again our great prime minister
shri
nehru rejected it outright he said not
at the cost of china china has to become
a permanent member first
then we will consider we will think
about it
and that's how china became one of the
five
permanent members of the un security
council
and today india is forced to
well sort of plead its case in various
circles worldwide
so that is how our great
prime minister daruji in a great uh act
of foresight apparently
decided to deprive his country and his
people of this
of this position on the u.n security
council that would have served india so
much
so it makes one wonder whom did mr nehru
actually serve
so yeah so that's about it for today's
questions thus far let me take some live
questions
some live chat questions let me see
what are you guys asking me
let me remove that question first here
we are
okay raja ramon roy karna polishing
shrikar asks
i've read that raja raman roy played a
big role in decent sweetheartization and
changing the education of systems
education system of india with macaulay
he has been given undeserving over
credit my views
so yes i agree that uh mr ram mohan roy
has been glorified to the heavens he
actually had
very strong anti sanskrit views he had
very strong anti-hindu views
he was buried in england he was not
cremated which makes one wonder what
as to what his actual religion was and
if you read his own
letters to the british it's very clear
how anti-hindu and how anti-sanskriti
was
i think i will make a separate video in
which i show all this in great detail
so that there is no uh
so there is no ambiguity about this so i
agree with you you are absolutely right
and i will
i think i will put this on my to-do list
i'll make a video about this a separate
video about this
shobajit asks what were the main reasons
for
india's independence was it a
combination of ww2 world war ii and
subhash bose's ina
the reason for india's independence was
very simple the british
had nothing more to gain from india they
had extracted
and leeched everything that was to leech
out of india
all the reserves of diamonds were gone
all the silver was gone
all the gold was gone india had been
depleted of every single resource they
could imagine off
right so there was nothing more to do
india's gdp was now less than two
percent of the entire world's gdp
india was a broken nation india's life
expectancy was less than 30 years
so there was no point trying to govern
such a broken
disastrously ravaged country and that's
why they lo
they implemented their exit strategy and
after the second world war they were
in no position to govern a territory so
far away it was a big burden for them
because there was nothing more coming
out of india they would have had to
actually
send something back to india to govern
it in an efficient manner
so it was that that caused india's
so-called independence
the second world war did contribute to
some extent to this
so bosh bose's ina did not contribute to
it unfortunately
i i it is regrettable the kind of uh
treatment that was meted out to the to
sebastian ribose firstly and to the ina
soldiers as well but in the grand scheme
of things the ina did not really play
that much of a role
they were defeated in in northeastern
india manipur etc
sadly regrettably
okay let's take a few more questions
why is india so diverse that's what
aditya asks
it's because india is not a nation state
india is a civilization state it is a
subcontinental
subcontinent-sized civilization state
india has the greatest genetic diversity
of any population
outside of africa and yet paradoxically
the entirety of india's population is
still genetically quite uniform
that is the paradox of india there is
incredible genetic diversity in india
and yet there is genetic uniformity and
there is a great deal of cultural
diversity as well there is a single
overarching culture from balochistan to
burma
from afghanistan to sri lanka and the
maldives historically
and yet there were so many local
manifestations of india's culture
because india's culture is so diverse i
just spoke about the various schools of
thought of indian philosophy
there are so many schools of thought of
indian philosophy some are agnostic
some are atheistic some are
materialistic some are deeply
deeply ritualistic some are
some are theistic some are scientific
some are philosophical and spiritual
there is everything is
accepted in in indian culture for
thousands of years
and these are the reasons why india is
so diverse the same gods and goddesses
are
worshiped in a variety of ways across
india you have durga puja in bengal
and you have navratri in gujarat this is
this is two thousand kilometers apart
nearly
and they are they are worshiping the
same goddess and celebrating the same
goddess
in very different ways you have kamaka
devi temple in assam
and you have hinglaj mata temple in
balochistan they worship the same
goddess
so far apart thousands of kilometers
apart from each other so this is the
beauty and the paradoxical beauty of
india there is such diversity
and yet there is one overarching culture
in india isn't that
interesting it's a unique place there's
no place like india and
like india in the world
now sir
okay let's take a few questions
few more questions
christopher asks does india have any
alien interactions
recorded uh well none that i know of
uh i believe there are certain temples
that have some alien like
carvings or sculptures or something i
think i need to watch more of praveen
mohan's very interesting channel but
as far as i know i may not know enough
but as far as i know that
we there doesn't seem to be any to my
knowledge
my knowledge is not perfect so that's
what i know
okay some more questions
uh who are the gorkhas and how do they
come to india are they different from
the nepalese people of nepal etc
yeah who are the gorkha people uh
the goldka people are a nepalese and uh
ethnicity
so let's look at the origin of the of
the gorkha people
i believe they have something to do with
baba ravel and
and guraknath the great saint
gorakhanath
so i believe that baba raval was a great
rajput warrior who conquered
various a great region in north western
india
punjab parts of afghanistan if i am not
entirely mistaken
so he was a great warrior a great
conqueror he repelled the turkic
invasions
for some time and restored civilization
for some time in northwestern india
eventually i think that he and his
followers
the rajputs went to according to legend
they went to the northern part i mean
they were the followers of
this great saint gaurant
so eventually once their work was done i
think
the great saint gaurant instructed them
to go to the northern part of india and
settle down there
and therefore they went to this power
this northern part of india
the newar valley or thereabouts present
the nepal region of
north of india today they settled down
there they intermarried among the locals
and they were devotees of the saint
gaurant
and that's how they came to be known as
the gorkhas and their descendants
still have that uh martial tradition the
rajput
martial tradition and that's why they
are such great warriors the gorkhas
so i believe from what i understand
according to legend this is the
origin of the gorkhas the gorkhas are
clearly
an indo-tibetan people or in
a tibet of berman people if i am not
completely mistaken but that is the
legendary origin of the gorkhas
so they are hindus they are the
descendants of rajputs and their local
people
and they are great warriors and they are
definitely people of nepal yes
how are they different from the people
of nepal well the whole of india is a
mix of various
different uh ethnic groups and so is
nepal
the gorkhas are very much nepalese
people so what the differ
saw that saw the descendants of the
kirata people so are the madesi people
they're all nepalese
there is no such thing as historical
nepal nepal came into being in the 18th
century
through the conquests of uh of that king
so it's a very new uh political entity
and so the gorkhas are definitely very
much
a part of the nepalese population they
are the people of nepal yes
yes yes i am aware of this i think
hundreds of people are trying to tell me
this i am aware of it i will send in my
suggestions to the government of india
and one hopes that it will well it will
correct
what's the the textbooks the ncert
textbooks
let's see what happens
okay let's take a few more questions
okay i will try and do that perhaps
okay why why is the indian government
not trying to retrieve the prices less
relics like nataraja and kohinoor from
the british museum it's a good question
it's a good question why isn't the
indian government doing this
so here's an interesting anecdote
yesterday i was on a news channel called
news x
it's an indian news channel so i was on
one of their live telecasts
recently there has been an
archaeological finding in orissa
they have found a 4 000 year old
archaeological site there
so music had invited me to uh give my
opinion about that
so there was this this government
official on the live telecast a very
nice gentleman from orissa
so he was saying that we have the money
but we don't have time
so we have only been able to do a little
bit of excavation because of the
pandemic and all that
but we have the money so i asked this
gentleman
if you have the money why don't you
why doesn't the indian government or
every indian state government
why can't they invest in one single
world-class museum in each state
why can't we have at least one just one
let's say to start with
one world-class museum in each state in
which we can
house our our priceless heritage and
display it to the world
and display to our own people in order
to increase awareness of our own history
and the connection of people with their
local history why can't we do this
let me tell you there is not one single
world-class museum
in the entire country of india
and we have the money so why can't we do
this
and why can't we retrieve our priceless
relics that have been stolen from us
illegally
such as the kohinoor and the nataraja
and and thousands more
in england and other countries why can't
we do it
and this gentleman said that this is a
million dollar question and he was
unable to answer my question
so the fact is that every state
government has more than enough money
to invest in at least one world-class
museum
in india in each state and the central
government can also fund these
such projects but there is a lack of
political
will there is a lack of willingness to
invest in these things
maybe the money has better uses i don't
know
so this is all about a lack of will
there is no there is no will to build
museums in india world-class museums and
there is no will to bring
these priceless relics back from the
places where they have been kept
so it is the fault of the indian
government we need to find a way of
making them hear us right
because the ministry of whatever it is
culture is it culture
it's a complete non-performing ministry
i mean what are they doing for india's
culture
it's a waste of taxpayer money it's a
waste of
taxpayer money
all right let me take
one more question
did you hear what i said sir i am sure
the mysore kingdom existed before the
portuguese or before
whoever after the british occupation of
india the mysore
kings the warriors were allowed by the
british to continue as kings
why was that because they paid
the price they agreed to abide by
british conditions the british laws and
british rules
that were imposed upon india by the
british if they had opposed
the british if they had opposed british
policies they would have been wiped out
i am sure they were good people many
kings were good people but they were
forced
to bow down to the british and
collaborate
with the british in order to continue
nominally ruling
their principalities and therefore these
are all
puppet kings they were allowed by the
british to continue
only in exchange for them abiding
to the conditions that the british set
upon them
so yes the warriors were puppets
one more question sir one more let's do
it
one more
this is a good one homie baba's death
mystery
so homie baba died in a plane crash i
think in the
swiss alps do you know where the swiss
alps are let me bring out the map i
haven't brought the
brought out the map today so let me
bring it out
okay let me share the
map
here is the map let's go westwards
the swiss ops
so i think it is somewhere here in this
region
south of switzerland near italy near
france
it's somewhere around here that
mr homi baba's plane crashed
and no investigation was done into this
plane crash
this the the wreckage of this plane this
this plane crash was not discovered
until many decades later because nobody
bothered to look into it
so the strange thing is that when a
plane crashes lots of people die
and the local government invariably has
the duty to go and investigate the plane
crash
and try and retrieve the wreckage and
try and retrieve the bodies for a proper
funeral and that was never done
so there is the very strong possibility
that this plane was sabotaged or brought
down
through artificial means in order to
deprive india of
what of the person who was its top
nuclear scientist
at the time there is a very strong
possibility
so even today the the exact cause of the
plane
crash has not been ever determined
so it's a mystery and uh yeah it's it's
possibly something that was engineered
by a foreign power
in order to set back india's nuclear
power program
because that's because india was going
ahead with a nuclear program at the time
okay i think we are done for today it's
been
90 minutes nearly so thank you everybody
for your questions
it's been great interacting with you and
we will continue
next week thank you very much for your
time thank you for watching
and i will see you soon good night good
day